TUSHAR GOYAL

: tushgoyal.github.io

□: +91-8561878657

Experience Summary

Around 5.4 years of experience in software application, analysis, design, Implementation and development using **React JS**, **Redux**, **Knockout JS**, **Angular JS** (1.x), **JavaScript**, **HTML5**, **JSP**, **CSS**, **Bootstrap**, **JSON**, **web services** (**Rest**). Apart from the technical skills having good understanding in functional requirements and software life cycle.

Professional Experience

Current Employer: **Brillio Technologies, Pune (From Feb 2021 to present)**Previous Employer: **Mediaocean Asia Pvt. Ltd, Pune (From Jan 2019 to Feb 2021)**Previous Employer: **Fujitsu Consulting India, Pune (From June 2016 to Jan 2019)**

Education Summary

- Bachelor of Technology (CSE): 2016 | Arya college of Engineering & IT, Jaipur | 70.24%
- Class 12th | RBSE: 2012 | Railway Senior Sec School, Abu road | 65.40%
- Class 10th | RBSE: 2010 | Adarsh Vidhya Mandir, Abu road | 81.33%

Technical Summary

- Front-End Development based on Single Page Application design utilizing Html5, CSS, JavaScript, JSP, Bootstrap, Knockout JS, React JS, Redux, Saga, Angular JS-1.6, Angular Material Design, Ui-Bootstrap.
- Experience on various JavaScript libraries like **React JS**, **Knockout JS**, **Lodash**, **Underscore JS**, **moment JS**, **require JS**, **Sanitize JS**, **Chart JS**, **jQGrid**, **Handsontable**, **select2**, **AgGrid**, **datatable**.
- Good understanding of React.js and its core principles including Virtual DOM, Data Binding, State
 Props and React Lifecycle Methods, Redux Architecture and Middleware such as Saga.
- Experience on implementing web applications in **Responsive design and Adaptive design**.
- Worked on task runner, package manager and bundler like **Grunt, Yarn, webpack, Maven, npm, Bower, Jenkins, Sass, and Docker.**
- Working experience in various editors and tools like **IntelliJ**, **Eclipse**, **Atom**, **Visual Studio Code**, **Notepad++**, **Sublime-Text**, **Squirrel**, **pgAdmin**, **SonarOube**, **Docker desktop**.
- Experience in version control using SVN, GIT-HUB, GIT-LAB, and Stash.
- Experience in **development for MVC patterns and RESTful Services**.
- Working experience in agile methodology.
- Experience on defect management tools like JIRA, tracking tool like Kibana.

Personal Details

Date of birth : June 20, 1994Languages : English, Hindi

• Interest : Dance, Mobile Photography, Playing Guitar, Swimming and Social networking.

Projects

Project Name	NSA (Verizon, US)	Team Size	25
Start Date	March 2021	End Date	present
Role & Contribution	 Migrating NSA application's frontend into React JS. Handling modules and delivering user-stories as per the product need. Contributing to code review and bug-fixing. Leading two separate module and handling the team of UI developers. Received "Brillian of the Month" for ownership and accountability within the project. 		
Technology & Tools	React JS, Redux, Redux-Saga, HTML 5, CSS, npm, webpack, bower, VS-code, Jira, Jenkins, Git- Lab, Source-tree, Kibana.		

Product Name	Prisma (Mediaplan-Buy)	Team Size	13
Start Date	Feb 2019	End Date	Feb 2021
Role & Contribution	 Feature implementations and enhancement in the product. Developing user stories into end-to-end module releases. Taking care of UI development in all different module within the product. Associating in production bug and defect fixing. Received "Achievement Award'20" for the excellence performance within a year. 		
Technology & Tools	Knockout JS, JavaScript, React JS, Bootstrap, HTML 5, CSS, npm, yarn, grunt, bower, IntelliJ,		
	Jira, Jenkins, Git, Stash, and Docker.		

Project Name	Fujitsu Cloud Service Management (product)	Team Size	10
Start Date	May 2018	End Date	Jan 2019
Role & Contribution	 Complete redesigned the existing implementation of the product. Worked on the front-end for all the applications for the project. Suggested and created new way to the client for enhancing user centricity. Implemented user stories during the sprint releases. Recognized by "Spotlight Award" for on time delivery. 		
Technology & Tools	JSP, Bootstrap, HTML 5, CSS, Angular JS, Postgres, Eclipse, VS-Code, pgAdmin, Git-Lab, SonarQube, Spring Boot and Hibernate.		

Project Name	Pricing Tool (Fujitsu, UK)	Team Size	5
Start Date	Jan 2017	End Date	April 2018
Role & Contribution	 Worked from scratch development. Developed and implemented end-to-end modules individually. Developed design documents and provided estimates for the client requirements. Styled content and screens layout for the user experience using CSS3 and Bootstrap Designed and developed UI/UX screens for the application. 		
Technology & Tools	Angular 1.6, Angular Material, Bootstrap, HTML 5, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, MySQL, Eclipse, Squirrel, SVN, Spring Boot and Hibernate.		

Declaration

Hereby declare that all the above furnished information is true to best of my knowledge and belief. The originals will be produced as required.